Guide to the Jack Oliver papers, 1911-2004.
Oliver, Jack papers
- The Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP)
  - Some Deep Seismic Reflection Profiling Slides (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Guatemala Earthquake Slides and Captions (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous
  - Misc. Slides, 21 (Box 13)
  - Misc. Slides, 22 (Box 13)
  - "Viewing Earth - Mountains and Volcanoes", 23 (Box 13)
  - Misc. Slides, 24 (Box 13)
  - US-Japan Earthquake Prediction Conference Slides, 25 (Box 13)
  - "Viewing Earth - Fault and Rift Zones", 26 (Box 13)
  - Misc. Slides, 27 (Box 13)
  - Resume of the geology of South America (Box 13, Folder 4)
- The States and Other Areas
  - "A Major Thrust Fault at Towanda, PA" (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Slide Set Descriptions (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Rocks and Routes of the North Country, New York" (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Glacial Geography of the Catskills" (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "The Geology of NY State" (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Maps (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ossipee, New Hampshire Earthquakes, December 20 and 24, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - J. Oliver - Old Biographical Information (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Aeromagnetic and Other Maps (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Field Guides Minnesota" (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Intro to Geologic Sciences 102 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - NY State Geological Survey - Empire State Geogram, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Geology (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "The Geology of New Hampshire", 1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Ohio - Lecture Notes, Etc. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ohio - Office File (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Ohio - Misc. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Ohio - Geology (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Ohio - Geology [Legal Sized Folder] (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - New York Geology (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Goshen-Greenwood Lake (Starling Forest) (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "Seismicity and its Relation to Geology (NY State)", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Geology and Physiographic Maps - New York Area (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - New York State Gravity Maps [Legal Sized Folder] (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Survey of Cayuga Lake, 1974-1978 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - "Underground Disposal of Liquid Waste in New York" (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - "Pre-C. Geology of the Popolopen Lake Quadrangle", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - "Magnetic Deposits of the Sterling Lake, NY Area...", 1952 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - New York Academy of Science - "Modern Aspects of the Geology of NY", 1958-1959 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Aeromagnetic Maps - NY Area, 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Excerpts from "Atlas of American Geology" (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Field Trip - NYC to Delaware Water Gap (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Reprints - NY Area (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Pennsylvania Geology (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - "Stratigraphy and Structure of the Stissing Mountain Area, NY", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - "Geology and Land Uses in the Pine Bush Area, NY", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - "Engineering Geology of the Northeast Corridor", 1967 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - "Correlation of the Silurian and Devonian Rocks in NY State", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Transparencies (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Geology of New York - A Short Account", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Geologic Map of Mt. Washington Area (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut West Quadrangle Geology, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - New Hampshire and Maine Maps (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "Geology Manual for Civil Engineering 1s" (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Nova Scotia Map (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - USGS Aerial Photo, June 1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Campus Building Stone (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - "Simplified Lithotectonic Synthesis of Pre-Silurian Rocks in Western New England", 1983 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Papers, 1992-1994 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - AAAS - G + G Section Meetings (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - AAAS Travel (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Ivrea Zone Field Trial (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Switzerland Field Lit. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Maps (Moscow and Czechoslovakia) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Kenya (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - New Mexico Geological Highway Map (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - California, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Oklahoma, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Rhinegraben Field Trip, October 1967 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - "Regional Hydrogeology of the Navajo and Hopi Indian Reservations..." (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Andesite Conference Proceedings (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - "The Story of Earthquakes..." Draft, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Nevada Geology (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Maps (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Grand Canyon Field Trip (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Rio Grande Graben Conference, August 11-16, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - International Geologic Conference (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - AFOSR Committee Photos (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Carnegie Institution Seismology Award (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Harry Oscar Wood Fund (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - SEG - Academic Industry Liaison Seminar (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Seismological Society of America, October 27-30, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Mineral Pamphlets (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - U.N Consulting - Vardar Project (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - NY State Map [Legal Sized Folder] (Box 15, Folder 38)
- Events and Trips
  - Executive Committee Binder, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Binder, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Council Meeting Agenda, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Hawaii (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - San Diego and LA, November 1999 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Seattle - AAAS (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - San Francisco - AGU, December 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - CB's Kansas City, May 2000 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Arizona, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Sante Fe (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Denver - GSA, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Memphis (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Minneapolis - Mayo (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Jazz Fest, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Cape Cod, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Maine, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Press - NAS, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - GSA - Reno, November 2000 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - GSA, October 1998 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Elder Hostel, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Jekyll Island - Elder Hostel (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Jazz Fest - Connecticut, August 2000 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - WHS Reunion (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Texas, February 2000 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Greece, May 1997 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Cabot Professorship - University of Houston (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - University of Houston - Visit by Jo, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Stanford - Advanced Building of Earth Science Meeting, March 1984 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Stanford - Advanced Building of Earth Science Meeting, April 1985 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Stanford - Advanced Building of Earth Science Meeting, March 1986 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - J. Oliver's Contacts Book and Journal (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Travel Brochures and Guides (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Various publications, guides, maps (Box 17-18)
  - Oliver's copy of Geology of the New York City (Catskill) aqueduct, inscribed by the author, Charles P. Berkey, to Dean L. A. Goetze. Map pocket in back, published by the New York State Education Department, Albany., 1911 (Box 17)
  - Two notebooks of Oliver's visits to points of interest in New York. Locations that Oliver traveled are noted, also includes his notes on the geologic information on the places. (Box 17)
  - Various Publications by Jack Oliver (Box 17)
- Unfiled, bound papers
  - New England Intercollegiate Geological Conference Guidebook, October 4-6, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Eastern Section: American Association of Petroleum Geologists - Guide for Field Trip, April 16, 1966 (Box 18)
  - "Tectonic Setting, Chemical Petrology and Petrogenesis of the Cortland Complex and Related Igneous Rocks of Southeastern NY State" - Guidebook Field Trip 1, 1983 (Box 18)
  - "Middle and Upper Ordovician Sandstone-Shale Sequences of the Mid-Hudson Region West of the Hudson River" - Guidebook Field Trip 2, 1983 (Box 18)
  - The Geological Society of America Guidebook of Excursions, NYC and Vicinity, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Guide book for Fieldtrips in CT, New England Intercollegiate Geological Conference, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, October 25-27, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Middle and Upper Devonian Clastics, September 24-28, 1979 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 31st Annual Meeting - Geology of the Cayuga Lake Basin, May 8-9, 1959 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 31st Annual Meeting - Geology of the Cayuga Lake Basin - 2nd Edition, May 8-9, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Geological Studies of the Northwest Adirondacks Region, May 7-9, 1971 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 50th Annual Meeting Guidebook, September 23-24, 1978 (Box 18)
  - "Meta-Anorthosite of the Jay-Whiteface Nappe, Ausable Forks-Lake Placed Quadrangles, Northeastern Adirondacks, New York" (Box 18)
  - New York Geological Association 36th Annual Meeting Guidebook, May 8-10, 1964 (Box 18)
  - The New York State Geological Association 44th Annual Meeting Field Trip Guidebook, September 15-17, 1972 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association Guidebook to Field Excursions, May 1968 (Box 18)
  - Deglacial History of the Lake Champlain - Lake George Lowland (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 39th Annual Meeting - Guide book to Field Trips, May 5-7,1967 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association Guidebook to Field Excursions, May 1969 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 32nd Annual Meeting - Guidebook to Field Trips, May 13-14, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Guidebook to Field Trips - New York State Geological Association 33rd Meeting, May 12-13, 1961 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 34th Annual Meeting - Field Guide Book, May 4-6, 1962 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 30th Annual Meeting - Field Guide Book, May 9-11, 1958 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 29th Annual Meeting - Geology of S.W. Tier Oil and Gas Fields, May 9-12, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Geology of the Wine country of New York, July 20-28, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Geological Studies of the Northwest Adirondacks Region, May 7-9, 1971 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 35th Annual Meeting - Geology of South-Central New York, May 3-4, 1963 (Box 18)
  - The Geological Society of America and Associated Societies - Guidebook for Field Trips, 1957 (Box 18)
  - The Ogdensburg Culvers Gap Moraine, 1961 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 38th Annual Meeting - Geology of Western New York, 1966 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 37th Annual Meeting - Field Trips in the Schenectady Area, April 30- May 2, 1965 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association 59th Annual Meeting - Field Trip Guidebook, November 6-8, 1987 (Box 18)
  - International Advanced Course on Exposed Cross Sections of the Continental Crust - Field Guides, September 17-27, 1988 (Box 18)
  - International Advanced Course on Exposed Cross Sections of the Continental Crust - Programme, Abstracts and List of Participants, September 17-27, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Geology Hydrology and History of the Washington, D.C. Area, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Geology of New York - A Simplified Account (Box 18)
  - Boston to Buffalo, in the Footsteps of Amos Eaton and Edward Hitchcock, June 28 - July 8, 1989 (Box 18)
  - International Geological Congress, Guidebook of Excursions - NYC and Vicinity, 1933 (Box 18)
  - The Geology of New York State, 1962 (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Association Guidebook, 1973 (Box 18)
- Contents of Large Folder in Box 18
  - Ithaca is Gorges Part III: Watkins Glen (Box 18)
  - "Continental Collisions and Ancient Volcanoes: The Geology of Southeastern New England", July 1980 (Box 18)
  - "Continental Collisions and Ancient Volcanoes: The Geology of Southeastern New England", July 1980 (Box 18)
  - "New Mountains from Old Rocks: The Adirondacks" (Box 18)
  - "New Mountains from Old Rocks: The Adirondacks" (Box 18)
  - "Building Stones of the Empire State Plaza", December 1986 (Box 18)
  - "Building Stones of the Empire State Plaza", December 1986 (Box 18)
  - Building Stones of our Nation's Capital (Box 18)
  - New York State Geological Highway Map, 1990 (Box 18)
- Later Additions
  - Employment Agreements with Government Agencies (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Wood Fund (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Past Travel (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Personal (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - CRC Press (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1988- (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Salisbury, G (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Sauage - Himalaya Study (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Sbar, Mare (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - SEG (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "S" (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sykes, Lynn R. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sigma XI (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Department Seismology Research (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Spence, David (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - "T" (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Tali (Alaska) (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - "U" (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - "V" (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - "W" (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - World Bank, NSF, Doug Johnson (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - "X,Y,Z" (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Stanford University - Annual Report (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Noureddine Beghoul (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Art of Discovery (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Retirement (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Ken Olsen - History of Nuclear Explosion Seismology (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - M. Kaufman - Article - Macmillan (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Science and Religion (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Friedensville Mine - Bob Metsger (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Jess Walker (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Geology 788 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Kentucky (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Columbia Interview with Jack Oliver, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Reprints for Amy (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Reprints for Amy (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Binder Contents - Cartoons and Overheads (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Transparencies for Physical Geology (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Sonic Boom Experiment, July 18, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Joszef Garai Article, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Dr. S. Das Envelope (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Jack Nafe (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Letters (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - D. Deming (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Charles Officer, Jack Page, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Frank Press - A.D. White Visit (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - John T. Kuo (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Chuck Drake (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - How the Earth Quakes Transparencies (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - How the Earth Quakes Folder (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Transparencies (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Podell Grant, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - "Shakespeare got it wrong..." Memoir (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Publications (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Handwritten notes and "Musings of an Aging Earth Scientist" (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Papers and Articles (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Limericks (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - The Ithaca Landscape - The Geological Story (Bound Folder) (Box 20)
  - Various Transparencies (Binder (Box 20)
  - Misc. Articles by Jack Oliver (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Papers and Articles (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Earthquake Education Materials for Grades K-12 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Bryan L. Isacks (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "The Chimeric Limerick Calender", 1997 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Articles and Publications (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The National Medal of Science, 2002, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Seismogenesis and Occurrence of Earthquake..." article, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Publications (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Misc. Papers and Articles (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - "Seismology - Responsibilities and Requirements" Parts I and II, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Talk for City Club, August 2000 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - "Directions in Solid Earth Science During the 21st Century", 1990 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Various Articles by Jack Oliver (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Various Articles by Jack Oliver (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Various Articles by Jack Oliver (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Science and Religion (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Cartoons (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - "Incomplete Guide to the Art of Discovery" cartoons (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - James Skehan (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Science and Religion Magazines (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Cartoons (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Washington H.S. - Massillon, OH (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - "Developpements Modernes del a Gravimetrie", 1947 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - "Shakespeare Got It Wrong" papers (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - "Incomplete Guide to the Art of Discovery" proof (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Papers, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - William Dickinson Letters, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Pratt, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Correspondences (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Medal of Science, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Papers and Articles (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - GSA (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - COCORP MSS in Prep (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Engr. - Resource Allocation Advisory Comm. (RAAC) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - A.D. White Professors-At-Large Selection Committee (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - E67-8109 (church) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - COPSTOC Talk (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - New Mexico Tech (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Rice (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Reading List - Geology G9945 - Seismology Seminar, 1962 through 1971 (Spring) (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Recent Crustal Motions Take Home Exams, Fall 1973 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Written Exams (Pre- Oral) (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Distinctions (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Geodynamics Comm. - Wash, April 4th, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Tyler Prize (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Misc. and Jack's Personal (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - SSA Medal - F. Press (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - DLT - Confid. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Dean Streett (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - L. Brown - Macel. Award Conference (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Fac. Meeting, Friday September 22, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - J. Oliver - Vitae + Pub.; Who's Who Forms (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - J. Oliver - A/Y Activities Report (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Hamilton College Honorary DSC Degree, May 22, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Texas A+M - pl. tec. (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - AAAS - Fellow Certificate (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Wegenar Medal (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Walter Bucher Medal, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - SSA Medal (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - GSA (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Shocks and Rocks (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Press, Frank - AD White (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Reviews of Proposals (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Geology of Physics (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Bernie VDH (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - McDonnell + McD. (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Journals (Excess) (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Northwestern (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - J. Salisbury (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - U. of Maryland (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Spots and Stains (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - J. Salisbury paper (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Ortelius (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - Phil Liu - Cayuga Lake (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - Brill - Creativity (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - Science PHDs in the high schools (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - Correspondences (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - National Medal of Science (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - CAPE (Emeriti) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - GSA Foundation (Bob Fuchs) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The Scientist issue, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Emeritus for J.O. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Vita and Pubs - J.O. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Doel and Barth (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - LDGO Oral History (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Limericks (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Strahler, Art (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "Shakespeare Got It Wrong" Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Grad Students (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Grad Students (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Acoustic EQs (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - EAS External Review, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Articles and Essays (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Articles and Essays (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Periodicals (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Obama at NAS, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Articles (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Sketches (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Misc. Articles and Sketches (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Papers (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Sketches (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - "Shakespeare Got It Wrong..." bound book (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Earth Story Notebook contents (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Funeral Mass program (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Culotta, Pratt, and Oliver - Geology, July 1990 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Oliver - The Spots and Stains of Plate Tectonics, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Oliver - Creative Thinking - Make it a Habit, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Lamont Reunion and Columbia (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Oliver - COCORP Probes Continental Depths, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Deep Seismix (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - John Elliott Nafe Memorial, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - GSA Today, 1996, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Misc. Articles, 1992-1995 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Cornell Publications, 1981-1993 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - "Geology of the Wine Country of NY", 1989 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Sketches and Drawings (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - "What Does It All Mean?" Paper (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Misc. Articles and Clippings (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - The Collected Reprints of Jack Oliver, 1951-1991 (Box 24)
    Contains four bound folders which consist of the complete collection of Jack Oliver's articles.